"왕좌의 게임"에 나온거야
It's from
Game of Thrones.
어때?
What do you think?
잘 모르겠어
I don't know.
판타지에 나오는 칼들을 모을거면--
If we're going to start
a fantasy sword collection--
사실 예전부터 그러고 싶었는데--
and I've long thought
we should--
이 칼부터 모으는게 맞을까?
is this really
the sword to start with?
그럼 어떤게 좋은데?
What did you
have in mind?
음, 일단 떠오르는 건, 엑스칼리버부터
모아야겠어
Well, off the top of my head,
I'd have to go with Excalibur.
잉글랜드를 다스릴 힘을 준다잖아.
It gives you the right
to rule England.
그냥 영화에 나오는
복제품(replica)일 뿐이야.
It would be a replica
of a movie prop.
그렇네.
Fair enough.
그러면 짝퉁(replica) 잉글랜드를
다스릴 힘을 주겠지.
It'd give you the right to rule
a replica of England.
근데 여기에 엑스칼리버는 없네,
Well, they don't have
an Excalibur here,
어쩌지 그럼?
so what do you want to do?
음, 어려운데.
Mm. Tough decision.
"반지의 제왕"에 나오는 무기는
There's no weaponry from
Lord of the Rings
중국산 짝퉁도 안가져다 놨고...
forged in a Chinese sweatshop?
저기 "빌보 배긴스"의 칼로 하자
Just Bilbo Baggins' sword
over there.
어른 둘이 호빗 단검을??
멍청해 보이잖아.
Two grown men with a hobbit's
dagger; wouldn't we look silly?
됐어, 이걸로 하자.
Okay, let's go for it.
이거 내가 아끼는 건데
Oh, I see
you guys have
멋지지?
found my little treasure.
응.
Yeah.
그냥 뭐 괜찮네.
It's okay, I guess.
그냥 괜찮다고?? 죽여주는데?
Okay? It's magnificent.
쉿쉿쉿쉿
Buh-buh-buh-buh!
얼마에 팔거야?
What do you want for it?
음 TV 드라마에 나온 물건은
Oh, it's hard to put
a price on something
부르는게 값이긴 한데
that's a copy of something
that was on pay cable.
너네는 친구니까 250불 어때?
But for my friends,
let's say 250?
야 그건 너무 비싼데
Oh, that's pretty steep.
이거 한정판이야
Well, it's a limited edition.
딱 8천개밖에 없다고
They only made 8,000
of these bad boys.
8천개밖에 없어?
Only 8,000?
이거 놓치면 안되겠네 얼른 사자
We're wasting precious time.
Buy it.
기다려봐
Hang on.
좀 깎아줄수 없어?
Can you do any better?
장난해?
Are you kidding?
벌써 가족&친지 할인 해줬잖아
I'm already giving you
the friends and family discount.
들었어?
Oh, did you hear that?
가족&친지 할인 해준다잖아
We're getting the friends
and family discount.
할인 고마워 이걸로 할게
We are honored
and we will take it.
기다려봐 좀
Slow down.
200불?
Two hundred.
빨리 좀 하자
What are you doing?
250불도 깎아 준거라잖아
250 is already the
discounted price.
입 좀 닫고 있어봐
Will you shut up?
그럼 235불까지는 해줄게
Tell you what, I'll go 235.
에이 그래도 안되겠어
Nope. Maybe another time.
야 225불 최대한 깎은거야
Okay, 225-- my final offer.
사자! 사자!
Take it, take it.
200불
Two hundred.
아주 날 잡았네 오늘!
Man, you're killing me!
날을 잡아?
나는 숨도 못쉬겠어 지금
Killing you?
I can't breathe.
210불, 손해보고 파는거야
210, and I'm losing money.
손해보고 판다잖아 레너드.
미안해
Oh, now, we can't let him lose
money, Leonard. I'm so sorry.
210불에 아이언맨 헬멧까지 끼워서
210 and you throw in
the Iron Man helmet.
제 정신이야?
Are you crazy?
Robert Downey Jr. 싸인받은 거라고
That helmet's signed
by Robert Downey Jr.
근데?
So?
야 영화 주인공 싸인도 받은
Okay, if you're
going to question
플라스틱 헬멧의 중요성까지
the importance of an actor's
signature on a plastic helmet
의심해야 한다면
from a movie
based on a comic book,
우리가 살아있는 거도 의미가 없어!
then all of our lives
have no meaning!
그래 알았다
Okay, fine.
칼만 해서 210불
Just the sword, 210.
Thank you.
이번 주에는 고기먹을 수 있겠다
I can eat meat this week.
봤지?
See that?
40불이나 아꼈잖아.
I just saved us 40 bucks.
내가 예전부터 너 공부는
못한다고 했는데
I've long said, what you
lack in academic knowledge
생활력은 강하네.
you make up for
in street smarts.
포장해줄까?
You want me to wrap it?
아니 됐어
No, it's okay.
이 친구 가슴팍에 꽂아서 가지고 갈래.
I'm gonna stab my friend
in the chest.
안녕 스튜어트
Hey, Stuart.
아 안녕 윌
Ah, hey, Wil.
잘 있었나 윌 위튼.
Hello, Wil Wheaton.
안녕 쉘든
Hi, Sheldon.
칼 멋지네
Nice sword.
나의 소장용 칼 중의 하나지
It's part of
my sword collection.
- 넌 소장용 칼 없지?
- 없는데
- Do you have a sword collection?
- No.
그럴 줄 알았어.
I'm not surprised.
이거 니가 주문한 배트맨 612화
Here's the
Batman 612
Jim Lee 특별커버판이야
with the Jim Lee alternate
cover that you wanted.
멋지네, 얼마 주면 되지?
Awesome. What do I owe you?
40불.
40 bucks.
가격도 좋네.
Good deal.
병신.
Sucker.
가족&친지 할인되는지
물어보지도 않았어.
Didn't even ask for the
friends and family discount.
야 금요일에 우리 집에서 파티하는데,
Hey, I'm having a party
at my house on Friday,
너두 와.
and I was hoping
you would stop by.
여자들도 오지?
Will there be
girls there?
그럼 당연하지
Yeah, of course.
저번에는 없길래...
'Cause there
wasn't last time.
여자들도 올거야.
There will be girls.
너네들도 오고 싶으면 와도 돼
You guys are invited
if you want to come by.
Thank you.
All right, great.
다음에 보자
Later.
네 속셈을 알겠다
I see what you're doing.
내 숙적이 여는 파티에
You accept
an invitation
간다고 해놓고
to a party at the home
of my sworn enemy,
걔가 우리도 온다고 얘기했는데
he tells everyone we're
going to be there,
우리가 안오면 쟤는 쪽팔리겠지
and when we don't show,
he looks the fool.
구밀복검이네.
Fiendishly clever.
나는 진짜로 갈건데.
I was actually
thinking about going.
가서는 파티 별로라고 하면서
And then declaring
the party a fiasco
나오려고 하지? 그럼 쟤는
and storming out,
leaving him humiliated
손님들 앞에서 쪽팔리고.
in front of his guests.
괜찮은데.
Love it.
아니 라지랑 하워드 데리고 가서
잘 놀다 올건데.
No, I was gonna grab Raj and
Howard and have a good time.
오 잘됐네 남자들만 더오고
Oh, great, more guys.
윌 위튼의 남탕파티 시즌2 겠네...
It's gonna be another
Wil Wheaton sausage-fest.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
The Big Bang Theory 5x05
The Russian Rocket Reaction
Original Air Date on October 13, 2011
The Big Bang Theory 5x05
The Russian Rocket Reaction
Original Air Date on October 13, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
할 일 없는 고시생 김동근 제작
dk2039@naver.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
쉘든 물 좀 갖다 줄래?
Sheldon, can you
grab me a water?
그러던지
Possibly.
준다는 거야 안 준다는 거야?
Can you or can't you?
그렇게 간단한 문제가 아냐 레너드.
It's not that simple, Leonard.
그냥 넘어가는 법이 없네 그지?
It never is, is it?
SHELDON:
지금 시점에
At this moment,
우리의 관계는 상호 모순적인
our relationship exists
2가지 상태에 있어.
in two mutually
contradictory states.
네가 윌 위튼의 파티에 가거나
혹은 안가기 전 까지,
Until you either do not go
or go to Wil Wheaton's party,
너는 내 친구이면서 동시에
친구가 아니야.
you are simultaneously my friend
and not my friend.
지금 이 상태를 말하자면
I'm characterizing
this phenomenon
"슈뢰딩거의 우정"이라고 할까.
as Schrodinger's Friendship.
알았어 이제 물 좀 줄래?
Got it. Can I have my water?
당연하지
Of course.
니가 가져다 먹어 이 배신자야.
Now get it yourself,
you traitor.
대체 무슨 일이야?
Wait, what is going on?
니가 잊어버렸을까봐 말해줄게
In case you have forgotten,
"슈뢰딩거의 고양이"는
사고 실험으로서.....
Schrodinger's cat is
a thought experiment...
아냐 아냐 안 까먹었어
No, no, I didn't forget.
음 박스 안에 고양이가 있는데
열어보기 전 까지는
Um, there's this cat in a box
and until you open it,
죽었을 수도 있고 살았을 수도 있다.
it's either
dead or alive or both.
근데 네브라스카에서는 고양이가
Although, back in Nebraska,
our cat got stuck
캠핑용 박스에 갇히면 열어볼 필요가 없어
in my brother's camp trunk,
and we did not need to open it
그 안에 죽은 고양이가 종류별로 다 있거든
to know there was all kinds
of dead cat in there.
소박한 이야기에서
물리학 지식까지
Homespun stories,
knowledge of physics
그리고 안 똑똑해 보이는 가슴까지
and a bosom that defies it.
너 진짜 다 갖췄다 그지?
You're the whole package,
aren't you?
늦어서 미안해
Sorry I'm late.
좋은 소식이 있어
Uh, I got great news.
이번 봄에 우주 정거장에서 쓸
NASA picked my team's design
딥필드 우주 망원경 디자인을 뽑는데
for the deep field
space telescope that's going on
NASA에서 우리 팀을 뽑았어!
the International Space Station
this spring.
(all murmur excitedly)
정말 잘됐다 하워드!
Howie, that's wonderful!
축하해!
Congratulations!
좋은 소식 또 있어.
It gets better.
망원경 가지고 우주에 갈 때
Someone has to go up
with the telescope
외부 전문가가 따라가는데
그게 누굴까????
as a payload specialist,
and guess who that someone is.
Muhammad Li.
Muhammad Li가 누군데?
Who's Muhammad Li?
Muhammad는 세계에서 제일 많은 이름이고
Muhammad is the most common
first name in the world,
Li는 제일 많은 성이야
Li, the most common surname.
답을 잘 모르겠어서
As I didn't know the answer,
수학적 확률이 높은 걸로 찍었지
I thought that gave me
a mathematical edge.
바로 난데 쉘든
It's me, Sheldon.
나라고
It's me.
내가 바로 우주에 가게 됐어!
I'm going up in space!
말하자면 이제 나는 우주비행사야!
Technically, I'm an astronaut.
(all murmur excitedly)
정말 놀랍다!
That's amazing!
(chuckles)
잠시만
Hang on a second.
NASA에는 이제 우주왕복선이 없다던데
NASA doesn't have
a shuttle anymore.
우주에는 어떻게 가는거야?
How are you going
to get up there?
아주 좋은 방법이 있어.
Oh, well, it's really cool.
모스크바에 가면
나를 카자흐스탄에 데려가는데
You fly to Moscow,
they take you out to Kazakhstan,
거기서 러시아 소유즈 로켓을 타고
and then you get into a Russian
Soyuz rocket which shoots you
저궤도위성까지 가는거지
into a low earth orbit.
카자스흐탄 마피아가
로켓연료를 암시장에 팔아넘기면
Or just sits there on the launch
pad because the Kazakhi mafia
발사대에 앉아만 있다가 오는거고
sold the rocket fuel
on the black market.
러시아 로켓은 안전해?
Are those Russian rockets safe?
음 체르노빌을 만든 착한 애들이
Well, I mean, safe as it
can be when it was built
만들었으니 완전 안전하겠지?
by the good folks who
brought you Chernobyl.
건배라도 해야겠다
I'd like to propose a toast.
우주에 가는 것은 우리 모두의 꿈이었는데
The dream to go up into space
is one we all share,
하워드가 그걸 실현시켰어
and Howard's making that
a reality.
네가 자랑스러워
We're all very proud of you.
ALL:
건배
Cheers.
정말 기분좋은 건배였어
That was a lovely toast.
-잘했어
-Thank you.
Kudos.
Thank you.
동시에, 신물나는 건배라니
Simultaneously, a festival
of cloying cliches.
너 정말 별로다
You sicken me.
오늘 말이 없네.
You're really quiet.
기분 안 좋아?
Is everything okay?
괜찮아
Fine.
그냥 좀 피곤하네
Just a little tired.
너무 피곤하면 안되는데
I hope not too tired,
because I'm feeling
오늘따라 힘이 불끈불끈하거든
particularly masculine
right now.
합체준비 완료!
무슨 말인지 알지?
All systems go,
if you catch my drift.
무슨 말인지는 알지
I always catch your drift.
기분 안 좋은거 맞네
All right, well, something's
obviously bugging you.
왜 그래?
What is it?
어떻게 나랑 상의도 없이
I just can't believe
you signed up
우주에 가기로 결정할 수 있어?
for the space program
without even talking to me.
아 무슨 말인지 알겠다
Oh, I get it.
나 걱정돼서 그러는 구나
You're worried about me.
고마워 자기야
That is so sweet.
들어봐 NASA에는 이런 말이 있어
You know, there's a saying
we have at NASA.
"모로 가도 집에만 가면 된다"
What makes
the right stuff so right
(의역)
is that it always comes home.
그냥 말 하지마 하워드.
Just stop talking, Howard.
내가 우주비행사가 된다고 했을 때
This isn't the reaction
I expected
이런 반응 기대한 건 아니었는데
when I told you
I was gonna be an astronaut.
그럼 내가 어떡할 줄 알았는데?
What did you think
was going to happen?
솔직히 말해? 섹스
Honestly? Sex.
하워드
Howard.
이거 정말로 대단한 일이야
Do you realize
what a big deal this is?
우주비행사로 뽑히는 게 얼마나 큰 영광인데
What an honor it is to be
chosen to go into space?
그래 알았어
Yeah, I get it.
내 말은 결정할 때 나랑도
얘기해야 한다는 거지
I just wish you included me
in the decision.
우리는 부부가 될 거잖아
We're supposed
to be partners.
우리는 팀이라구
We're supposed
to be a team.
미안해 자기 말이 맞네
I'm sorry. You're right.
그럼 다시 말해볼게
Okay, let's try this again.
베르나데트, 우리 둘 모두에
관련된 얘기가 있는데
Bernadette, an opportunity
has come up
그 얘기 했으면 좋겠어
that impacts both of us,
and I'd like to discuss it.
그래
Okay.
국제우주정거장에 3주동안 가 있을
I've been offered
a chance to go up
기회가 생겼어
to the International
Space Station for three weeks.
어떻게 생각해?
What are your thoughts on that?
음 먼저 결정할 때
Well, first of all, thank you
내 생각도 해줘서 고마워
for including me
in the decision-making process.
우리는 팀인데 뭘
Hey, we're a team.
(chuckles)
그래서 어떻게 생각해?
So, what do you think?
안 돼
No.
안 된다고?
No?
안 돼
No.
왜 안되는데?
Why not?
하워드, 우리 아버지는 경찰이셨는데
Howard, my father
was a police officer.
매일 나가실 때마다 다음 날에
We never knew
from one night to the next
아버지가 살아서 돌아오실지조차
확실하지 않았어
if he was going
to come home alive.
정말 끔찍했다구.
It was horrible.
그래서 자기랑도 그런 식으로
살고 싶진 않아
And I don't want to live
that way with you.
우리 아버지는 내가 11살 때 집을 나가셨어
Hey, my father abandoned me
and my mother when I was 11.
그리고는 한번도 다시 보지 못했어
We never saw him again.
아 떽 우주는 안 된다니까!
Oh, boo-hoo,
you're not going to space!
하워드 정말 잘 됐다 그지?
Pretty cool about
Howard, huh?
우리 사이 괜찮은 것처럼 얘기하지마.
Don't talk to me as if
nothing's happened between us.
그리고 응 진짜 잘됐다.
And yes, it sure is, buddy.
미치겠네 슈뢰딩거 그거좀
그만하면 안될까?
For God's sake, will you stop
with the Schrodinger stuff.
그러면 더 간단한
Would you prefer
a simpler application
Heisenberg의 불확정성이론을
적용해 볼까?
of Heisenberg's
uncertainty principle,
네가 어디에 있는지 혹은
in which I could either
내가 널 좋아하는 지는 알 수 있지만
know where you are
or whether I like you,
둘다 동시에 알 수는 없는 그런거?
but not both?
진짜 끝이 없네 정말
You never stop
talking, do you?
이해가 잘 안 돼
I don't understand.
레너드가 윌 위튼 파티에 가든 말든
What differences
does it make
무슨 차이가 있어?
if Leonard goes to
Wil Wheaton's party?
윌 위튼은 쉘든의 불구대천지원수야
Wil Wheaton is
Sheldon's mortal enemy.
불구대천지원수?
Mortal enemy?
쉘든, 네가 비현실적으로
Mm-hmm.
Sheldon, I know you're a bit
괴짜라는 건 알지만...
of a left-handed
monkey wrench, but...
진짜 그 정도의 적(enemy)이 있어?
you really have a mortal enemy?
정확히 말하면 61명이 있지
In fact, I have 61 of them.
61명 목록 한번 볼래?
Would you like to see the list?
Oh, 아니라고 말 해 아니라고 말 해.
Oh, say no, say no,
say no, say no.
너 목록에서 지워진지 얼마 안 됐거든
You just got off the list.
다시 올라가고 싶어?
Would you like back on it?
잠시만 기다려봐.
This'll just take a moment.
5.25인치 디스켓에 있어.
It's on a five and a
quarter inch floppy.
디스켓?
A floppy disk?
아홉 살 때부터 목록을 만들었거든.
Well, I started the
list when I was nine.
윌 위튼은 어쩌다 거기 올라간거야?
How did Wil Wheaton
get on the list?
- 아 제발!
- 안돼!
- Oh! Oh, God!
- Oh! Come on!
어렸을 때 난 "스타트렉"에서
As a child,
I loved Wesley Crusher,
윌 위튼의 캐릭터 Wesley Crusher를 좋아했지
Wil Wheaton's character
on Star Trek.
그래서 몇 시간이나 버스를 타고
So, I drove for hours
by bus to a Star Trek convention
윌 위튼이 나오는 "스타트렉"
박람회에 갔어
at which Wil Wheaton
was scheduled to appear,
Wesley Crusher 액션 피겨에
싸인받고 싶었거든
so that I could get my Wesley
Crusher action figure signed.
그렇지만 그는 나타나지 않았어
But he never
showed, because
분명히 그는 Hollywood 광장의
apparently,
it was cooler for him
왼쪽 아래 모퉁이에 있는 게
더 좋았나 보지
to be the lower-left corner
on Hollywood Squares.
아 이런!
Oh, damn!
디스켓이 고장났어
The floppy failed.
흠
Well,
1989년에 Verbatim Corporation에서
whoever was in charge
of quality control
품질관리를 맡으신 바로 당신
at the Verbatim Corporation
in 1989,
축하합니다 방금 리스트에 올라가셨네요
congratulations,
you just made the list.
하워드?
Howard?
지금은 하고 싶어?
Change your
mind about sex?
아직 화났어도 난 할건데.
I'm still mad,
but I'll do it.
아니 생각 좀 해봤어.
No, I've just
been thinking.
내가 자기 걱정되는건 중요한게 아닌거 같아
It doesn't matter
if I'm afraid for your safety.
자기 꿈을 가로막는
I don't want
to be the person
그런 사람이 되고 싶진 않아
who stands between you
and your dreams.
정말?
Really?
정말
Really.
우주에 가는게 그렇게 의미가 크다면
If going into space means
that much to you,
그 얘기는 이제 더 이상 안할게
I will never say
another word about it.
고마워
Thank you.
사랑해
I love you.
나도 사랑해
I love you, too.
그럼 지금 할까?
So, sex now?
그래
Okay.
양치하는 걸 깜빡했어
I just forgot
to brush my teeth.
금방하고 올게
I'll be right back.
(rhythm and blues playing)
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ I'm ♪
♪ I'm not in love with you... ♪
MRS. WOLOWITZ: 내가 죽기 전엔
우주 못 가!
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Over my dead body
my son goes into outer space!
준비 다 됐어
I'm ready.
잠깐 내가 똑바로 들은거 맞아?
Wait, let me see
if I got this right.
한밤중에 베르나데트보고
You actually asked Bernadette
집에서 나가라고 했다고?
to leave your house
in the middle of the night?
그럼 어떡할까
What choice did I have?
걔는 나를 속이고
She went behind my back
엄마한테 일러바쳤다고
and turned my own mother
against me.
와우, 우리 중에 첫번째로
우주비행사된 거도 모자라서
Wow. You're not only
our first astronaut.
첫번째로 침대에서 여자를
차버린 사람이 되다니
You're also the first one
of us to kick a girl out of bed.
너 진짜 잘나간다
You're like a rock star.
내가 좀 그래
Little bit.
이런말 하긴 그렇지만
널 배신한거나 마찬가지네
I hate to say it,
but she did kind of betray you.
흥미롭군
Interesting.
남이 배신하는 건 보이는데
자기껀 안보이고
You see betrayal in others,
but not yourself.
위튼네 파티 가는 건 배신이 아니야
Going to Wheaton's party
is not betraying you.
오 당연히 넌 그렇게 생각해야지
Oh, of course you would have
to believe that.
나쁜 사람들은 항상 자기가
올바른 일 한다고 생각하잖아
Evil always thinks
it's doing right.
"저기 Stormtrooper님
"Excuse me, Stormtrooper.
찾으시는 droid 저기 있어요."(Star Wars)
These are the droids
you're looking for."
그냥 파티가는 것 뿐이야
I'm going to a party.
R2-D2랑 C-3PO를 제국에
팔아 넘기는 게 아니라고!
I'm not turning R2-D2 and C-3PO
over to the empire!
그거도 시간문제지
Not yet.
그래서 이제 어떡할거야?
So, what's gonna happen next?
베르나데트랑 헤어질거야?
Are you and Bernadette going
to break up?
모르겠어.
I don't know.
다시 화해하려면
If we're going
to get back together,
걔가 나한테 사과하고
she's going to have
to apologize and accept
내가 결정권있는 성인이란 걸 인정해야지
that I'm a grown man
who can make his own decisions.
그리고 너희 엄마 설득하는거는
Then she's going to have
to convince your mother
베르나데트가 하고?
to let you go into space.
그럼 그걸 내가 하겠냐
Obviously.
어쩔 수가 없었어
I had no choice.
걔네 엄마한테 말해야 했다고
I had to tell
his mother.
걔를 어떻게 우주에 보내
He can't go to space.
지 앞가림도 못하는 애기잖아
He's like a baby bird.
저번에 오래된 도서관 책 읽다가
Do you know
he once got an asthma attack
천식발작 온 거 알아?
from reading an old library
book?
에이 설마
You're kidding.
아니야 나도 그 날 있었어
No, I was there that day.
쉘든이 그 책 쥐여주고 내쫓아 버렸어
Sheldon threw his back out
handing him that book.
뭘 어떻게 해야 할지 모르겠다
I don't know
what I'm going to do.
이거 때문에 헤어지고 싶진 않아
I don't want
to break up over this.
그러면 그냥 실수했다고 말하는게 어때?
Okay, why don't you just
tell him you made a mistake?
내가 실수했다고 생각해?
Do you guys think
it was a mistake?
내가 잘못한건가?
Am I the bad guy in this?
우리가 판단할 문제는 아니지
It's not for
us to judge.
네가 얼마나 야비한 짓 했는지
알 때까지
We're just here to provide
comfort and support
우리는 그냥 얘기들어주고
while you come to grips
맞장구 쳐주는 거지 뭐
with what a despicable thing
you've done.
아 너희 말이 맞아
Oh, God, you're right.
내가 우리 사랑을 버스만한
걔네 엄마 밑에 뭉개버린거야
I took our love and threw it
under his bus-sized mother.
사과해야겠어
I need to apologize.
응 그렇게 생각하면 잘...잘됐네
Well, that-that's good.
I'm glad you came to that.
근데 그 전에 근본적인 질문
하나만 할게
But before you do, let me just
ask you a big picture question.
뭔데?
What?
너 정말로
Are you
하워드 왈로위츠를 사랑하고
결혼하고싶다고 100%확신해?
100% positive you love and want
to marry Howard Wolowitz?
확신하고 말고
I do, with all my heart.
(clicks tongue)
알았어
Got it.
그냥 좀 궁금해서
Just had to check.
좋은 사람이잖아!
He's great.
그러면 쉘든
All right, Sheldon.
우리 윌네 갔다 올게
We're going to Wil's.
지금이 마지막 기회야
This is your
last chance.
아니 레너드
지금이 너의 마지막 기회지
No, Leonard,
this is your last chance.
언젠가
One day,
역사가가 와서 이렇게 물어볼거야
a historian is going
to come to you and say,
"쉘든 쿠퍼 박사와 친구이셨다는게
사실입니까?"
"Is it true you were friends
with Dr. Sheldon Cooper?"
그러면 너는 후회와 굴욕의
And you're going to have
to choke back a hot sob
뜨거운 눈물을 억누르며 말하겠지
of regret and humiliation
"그랬었지만...
as you mumble,
"I was, but
"지금은 아무도 기억못하는
Stand By Me에 나온 사람
"I chose to go to a party thrown
by the one kid
그 사람 파티에 가고 말았습니다..."
from Stand By Me
that no one remembers."
네가 운전 할래?
You want to drive?
그래
Sure.
(door closes)
Hey, Sheldon?
아 역시 날 선택했지 그지?
Oh, good. You picked me,
you picked me.
아니 스튜어트한테 문자왔는데
No, I just got a
text from Stuart.
Brent Spiner가 파티에 온대
Brent Spiner is
at the party.
Brent Spiner?
응
Yes.
관심없어
I don't care.
정말?
Really?
Brent Spiner,
Mr. Data 바로 그 사람이라고!
너 좋아하잖아!
Mr. Data himself.
You love him.
그랬지만 이제 "스타 트렉"같은거
보던 시절은 지나갔어
I did, but I think I've kind of
outgrown Star Trek.
뻔한 캐릭터에 터무니 없는 줄거리
You know, stock characters,
"beam me up."
(스타 트렉 순간이동 대사)
ludicrous plots, "beam me up."
터무니 없는 소리지
What a load of hooey.
갈 게 그럼
I'm going.
Live long and prosper, 쉘든
(스타 트렉 대사)
Live long and
prosper, Sheldon.
그래 그거도 진짜 오타쿠같아
Yeah, even that.
You look like a dork.
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
하워드, 베르나데트 왔다!
Howard, Bernadette's here!
집에 없다고 해요!
Tell her I'm not home!
그게 무슨 말도 안되는 연기야!
What kind of a schmuck play
is that?!
니 목소리 다 들린다고!
She can hear you shouting!
얘기 좀 할까?
Can we talk?
그러던지. 나는 할 말 없어
You can. I have nothing to say.
그래
All right.
너희 엄마한테 일러바친거
I just wanted to tell you
사과하고 싶어
I'm sorry I said something
to your mother.
어쨌든 내가 말할 거긴 했지만
I was gonna tell her eventually,
너는 나를 속인거야
but you went behind my back.
알고있어 미안해
I know. I'm sorry.
겁나서 그랬어
I got scared.
나를 사랑하려면
If you're gonna love me,
내 모든 모습을 사랑해야지:
you're gonna have to
love the whole package:
자상한 시인과 미친 데어데블 둘다
the tenderhearted poet
and the crazy daredevil.
알아
I know.
진심이 아니면 그런 말 하지마
Well, don't say it if
you're not gonna mean it,
우주정거장 가는 게 끝이 아니야
'cause I'm not just gonna
stop with the space station.
나는 달도 가고 싶고 화성도 가고싶고
Yeah, I want to go to the
Moon, I want to go to Mars.
1인 잠수함을 타고
심해저에도 가고 싶어
I want to take a one-man sub to
the lowest depths of the ocean.
정말?
Really?
너 "캐리비안의 해적"보고
멀미했잖아
You got seasick
on Pirates of the Caribbean.
그건 너무 실감나서 그런거고
Well, those big kids
were rocking it.
너를 너무 사랑해서 그랬어
I just did what I did
because I love you so much,
그리고 널 잃을지도 모른다는 게
견디기 힘들었고...
and the thought of losing you
is more than I can handle.
그랬어?
Really?
넌 나의 소울메이트잖아
You're my soul mate.
지금 키스하면 돼
This is where you kiss me.
응응 그래 (laughs)
Right, right. (laughs)
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
아무리 발버둥쳐봐도
Make up all you want!
니 엉덩짝은 지구를 떠날수 없어!
Your tuchis is not
leaving this planet!
야 "First Contact"에서
Hey, you know
that beautiful actress who plays
the Borg Queen 역할했던 이쁜 애 알지?
the Borg Queen in First Contact?
- 응
- 나 방금 걔 산부인과 주치의 만났어!
- Yeah.
- Well, I just met her gynecologist!
여기서 뭐해?
What are you doing here?
우리 우정을 위해 싸우고 있지
Fighting for our friendship.
넌 괴짜고 짜증나기도 하지만
As peculiar and annoying
as you can be,
여전히 내 친구니까
you're still my little buddy.
우리 우정이 오늘 밤 끝나선 안 돼
I'm not going
to let that end here tonight.
이제 그 술 내려놓고 Brent Spiner만
보고 집에 가자
Now put down that drink, let's
meet Brent Spiner and go home.
헤이 쉘든 네가 오니 정말 좋다
Hey, Sheldon,
I'm so glad you made it.
네가 좋아할 만한거 챙겨놨어
I found something
I think you might like.
난 쟤네 집이 음울했으면 좋겠는데
What I'd like is for him
to have a more depressing home.
집 꽤 괜찮네
This is quite lovely.
자 여기
This is for you.
Wesley Crusher 액션피겨
풀패키지 진품이네
An original mint-in-package
Wesley Crusher action figure.
너 어렸을 때 여기에 싸인받으러
I remembered your story
about the time you went
박람회에 왔다가 내가 없었다고
to a convention
when you were a kid
했던 얘기 기억나서
to get one signed,
and I didn't show up.
내가 써놓은거 봐봐
Look at what I wrote.
"쉘든에게, 너무 오래걸려서
미안하구나
"To Sheldon, sorry
this took so long.
너의 친구, 윌 위튼"
Your friend, Wil Wheaton""
이거 하나 남았더라고
It's my last one.
너한테 주고싶어
I want you to have it.
여기 봐요, 윌 위튼이 내 친구임!
Look, everyone.
Wil Wheaton is my friend!
Oh, wow.
이런거 되게 오랜만에 보네
I haven't seen one
of these in years.
얘네가 DDR중인 거처럼
Remember how we used
to make these things look
낙서했던거 기억나?
like they were masturbating?
Brent Spiner, 뭐하는 짓이에요
Brent Spiner, what
have you done?!
그건 Wesley Crusher 액션피겨
That was an original
mint-in-package
풀패키지 진품이란 말입니다
Wesley Crusher
action figure
내 친한 친구 윌 위튼이
싸인까지 한건데
signed by my close personal
friend, Wil Wheaton.
미안해 멀대 같은 놈아
Sorry, Slim.
내 차 트렁크에
Mr.Data 인형있는데
I've got some Mr. Data dolls
in the trunk of my car.
싸인해서 갖다 줄까?
You want me
to sign one for you?
당신 이름 벌써 싸인됐거든요
Brent Spiner
You've already signed
something, Brent Spiner.
내 리스트에 이름 싸인됐어요
Your name on my list.
지금 이 순간부터,
당신은 나의 적입니다
From this moment on,
you are my mortal enemy.
걱정마세요 별거 아니에요
Don't worry. It doesn't take
up a whole lot of your time.
가자 친구
Come on, buddy.
이 루저한테 시간낭비하지 말자구
Let's not waste another
second on this loser.
너희 집 좋다
Love your house.
저희한테 싸인한 인형 좀 주실래요?
Can we get autographed dolls?
그럼
Sure.
20 불이다
20 bucks.
10불
Ten.
$18.
$12.
$16.
2개에 30불
Two for $30.
그리고 내 생일파티 오는 조건
And you come
to my birthday party.
좋아
Done.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==